Sanusi Bello



rafiubello4real@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/bello-olaniyan-42626b1b6



+2348027365891



https://sanbello.vercel.app/

Summary

Full Stack Developer up to 4 years of experience in web development and as a problem solver who loves facing challenges in my work, I'm excited to be at the deployment phase of my career as a web developer. I love to be on a team that questions possibilities. I've previously been a graphics designer, and bring those skills to my UI development on a team. Independently, I've Delivered 150% on sales targets for 3 consecutive years

Experience



MERN Stack Developer

Khristfix Technologies

Jan 2021 - Present

- Frontend development using React Js, HTML5, CSS3
- Backend development using Node Js, MongoDB and Express framework
- Prepare Technical Design and Specification documents
- Collaborate with the development team, support, and business on day to day development requests and support
- Prepare documentation and use case scenarios when required
- Leads solution designs, documents architecture proposals and creates high-level design **Documents**
- Lead technical solution sessions to ensure that solutions are complete, scalable and are future-Proof• Helps determine coding standards along with the senior development team and ensures consistent adoption by developers
- Conducts code reviews, mentors and coaches the larger team, provides objective feedback to consultants and development partners to ensure proper execution of projects.

Remote Frontend Developer (Contract)

FOREMAN ENTERPRISE

Mar 2020 - Jul 2021

- Participate in the entire application lifecycle, focusing on coding and debugging
- Write clean code to develop functional web applications
- Troubleshoot and debug applications
- Perform UI tests to optimize performance
- Manage cutting-edge technologies to improve legacy applications
- Collaborate with Back-end developers to integrate API endpoints
- Gather and address technical and design requirements
- Provide training and support to internal teams
- Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- Liaise with developers, designers and system administrators to identify new features Follow emerging technologies

Front End Developer / UI-UX Designer

Okitech

Aug 2017 - Dec 2019

- Design, test, code and deliver high quality secure production software with completely automated tests suitable for cloud deployment at scale
- Write clean, well-documented, and well-tested code using Test-Driven-Development.
- Develop automated tests (TDD including unit or behavioral test, integration test, acceptance tests) to achieve test coverage for continuous deployment and near 100% availability.
- Collaborate with CTO and Product Manager to refine epics, user stories and acceptance criteria
- Minimize technical debt and continuously improve and learn from mistakes, bugs and refactoring.
- Work in small deliverable batches Conduct research, spikes, design, prototyping and other innovation, exploration and learning activities.
- Eliminate distractions, impediments and wasteful work to optimize flow and velocity.
- Use software engineering best practices to ensure a high standard of quality.
- Help the team succeed in delivering potentially releasable and production ready software artifacts in every iteration.
- You will be assisting with technical direction, utilizing modern technology and Agile best practice to help create and deliver cutting-edge.
- Review & compare different technical solutions and applications/tools, and recommend the best considering security, performance, scalability and maintainability of solutions on Salesforce.

Education



University of Ilorin Bachelor of Science - B.Sc. Physics 2017 - 2021

Licenses & Certifications



Problem Solving Certificate - HackerRank



Certified CSS Developer - HackerRank



Responsive Web Design - freeCodeCamp



Certificate of Completion - Frontend Fundamentals - Pirple

Skills

Programming Language

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- (
- Python
- C++
- MatLab
- PHP

Operating System

- Windows
- Linux
- Chrome OS
- AR OS

Databases

SQL

- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- SQLite

NoSQL

- MongoDB
- FireBase

Hosting Platform

- Heroku
- Netlify
- Vercel
- Github
- Firebase Hosting

Frameworks / Libraries

- React
- Hooks
- Vue
- Next js
- Algorithm and Data Structure
- GraphQL
- Redux
- Nest Js
- Redux-Thunk
- Morgan
- Node JS

- Express
- Axios
- Webflow
- Webpack
- Gulp
- Lodash
- EJS
- Material UI
- Ajax
- Jquery
- Formik
- Styled Components
- Mongoose

Markup Languages

- HTML
- XHTML
- XML

Styling Technologies

- CSS
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind CSS
- Sass
- Bulma CSS
- Chakra UI
- Semantic UI

Other Technologies / Skils

- Glt
- CorelDraw
- Jira
- Adobe XD
- Github
- AWS
- PowerShell
- Bash
- Adobe Photoshop
- Command Prompt
- Microsoft word
- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft PowerPoint
- Microsoft Access
- Microsoft Publisher
- Webflow
- Adobe Illustrator

Honors & Awards



FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF KASHERE CHAPTER, GOMBE STATE

Programmer of the Year - NAPPS - National Association of Physics Student Feb 2022

University of Ilorin, Kwara State

PERSONAL / OPEN-SOURCE PROJECTS

- **Mazaryn** An open-source social application that implements blockchain technology for transactions among members of the application. (React, Python Django, PostgreSQL).
- **Trans-Logistics** A logistic application that allows users to send and receive goods and parcels across the nation. (React, Node JS and MongoDB).
- **JavaScript-Land-Community** An open-source application for javaScript that allows users to search for and create video recordings through the world (Next, Node and Mongo)
- **Tube-Pro** A personal project that grant users access to videos regarding their search terms integrated with YouTube API (React and CSS).
- **Sea-food-store** An e-commerce website where clients are able to load available sea foods and add it to their cart and it was made editable (React, Firebase and Stylus).
- Message-Encryption A web-based application for encrypting messages into links which can be decrypted only by the person that has the link (JavaScript, CSS and HTML).
- Movie-Comparer A website for comparing two movies in order to know which one more rated, built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Axios, bulma, OMDB API and Fontawesome

- **To-do app** A React JS web application for where users can create new tasks, delete an existing one and ticking the completed ones out. Built with React js, CSS, Axios and UUID.
- **Blog Post** An online blog platform, built with Node js framework, MongoDB, EJS, lodash, Morgan, FireBase and Express Js.